Akhator Osakhogba



Contact

City: Abuja

Phone:

+234 703 985 4258

Email:

aosakhogba@gmail.com

Website:

Personal Website Linkedin Profile

Languages

English

Summary

I am Akhator Osakhogba, alias Osa, specializing in front end development that brings front- and back-end design to promote organization-specific website presence. With comprehension of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL and Wordpress to generate custom webpage design. Detail-oriented approach to maintaining website responsiveness, effectiveness and security. Hardworking and passionate with strong organizational skills and ready to help team achieve company goals.

Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Responsive design
- CMS management
- PHP
- MySQL
- Service-focused

Experience

Freelance Web Developer- 2019 to Current

 Worked on different web development projects for businesses over the years.

System Support Analyst Intern- 03/2017 to 12/2017 Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC), Abuja

- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.
- Ordered, maintained and distributed supplies and inventory.
- Participated in continuous improvement by generating suggestions, engaging in problem-solving activities to support teamwork.
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.
- Devoted special emphasis to punctuality and worked to maintain outstanding attendance record, consistently arriving to work ready to start immediately.
- Engaged in daily operations to ensure high levels of productivity.

Software Developer Intern- 03/2017 to 12/2017 **Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC)**, Abuja

 Built and styled new mobile-friendly websites, transitioning legacy presentations to simultaneous easy-to-use versions.

- Assisted web presence planning, implementing changes and integrating requested elements to streamline business operations.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages.
- Converted graphic designs to usable web images using Adobe Photo Shop.
- Indulged back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.
- Ran debugging tools such as Firebug and Chrome Inspector to eliminate flaws and glitches prior to publishing.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science - 2021

Ambrose Alli University, Ekpoma